I remember those cheers,
they still ring in my ears,
and for years they remain in my thoughts,
'cause one night,
I took off my robe, and what'd I do?
I forgot to wear shorts.
I recall every fall, every hook, every jab,
the worst way a guy can get rid of his flab,
as you know, my life wasn't drab.
Though I'd much...
Though I'd rather hear you cheer when you delve...
Though I'd rather hear you cheer when I delve into Shakespeare...
"A horse! A horse! My kingdom for a horse!"
I haven't had a winner in six months.
And though I'm no Olivier, I would much rather...
And though I'm no Olivier, if he fought Sugar Ray,
he would say that the thing ain't the ring, it's the play.
So, give me a stage where this bull here can rage,
and though I can fight, I'd much rather recite.
That's entertainment.
Jake La Motta and Jimmy Reeves...
... in the Cleveland Arena.
La Motta is undefeated, but he's well behind on points.
The Bronx Bull has taken a lot of punishment in this bout.
Jake is cut around the left eye. Jimmy Reeves has outboxed him...
Jack, tell me why, why the fuck do we have to come to Cleveland for you
to get beaten by a mulignane?
Come on, do the fuckin' right thing.
He's got you by the balls, you're outpointed.
You're comin' up for the tenth, you're gonna have to knock him out.
I want you to bite him, kick him, do anything you gotta do.
Nobody's lookin', you know what to do.
Just like home... all over the fuckin' moolies.
Knock the motherfucker out. You understand? Knock him out.
Hey, you wanna go in there? You wanna go in and do it?
Help!
We need a knockout, let's go get a knockout,
that's where it's at.
Tenth and final round. Good luck to you both.
La Motta fighting out of a half crouch.
Reeves is up against a tough fighter,
a man who doesn't know how to back up.
La Motta continues to bore in, out of the bob and weave,
hooks a left hand to the jaw, and Reeves is down!
The crowd is urging Jake on.
The referee is tolling over Reeves. He's got to get up.
La Motta comes at him once again, Reeves misses a right,
takes a left, and another left, a hard left hand to the jaw,
and Reeves is down for the second time.
A determined Jake La Motta is making a great comeback
here in the tenth round.
Reeves is up again. La Motta comes at him.
A left hook to the jaw, another left, and a right to the body.
Three more lefts to the midsection, a hook on the jaw,
two more lefts to the head, a right and a left to the jaw.
Reeves goes down for the third time,
and the referee is pulling La Motta away.
Two... three...
four... five...
- The referee is counting over Reeves, - six... seven...
- but time is running out... - eight... nine...
...and there is the bell.
He can't walk, but Reeves has been saved by the bell.
But did La Motta do it soon enough?
Jack, Jack, come here.
It's no good. This is Ohio, not New York!
- You waited too long! - That dumb bastard!
Put the robe on right, huh? Put my robe on right!
Ladies and gentlemen...
...under the rules of the Ohio Boxing Commission,
after ten rounds,
the winner, by unanimous decision,
- Jimmy Reeves! - The colorful Jake La Motta,
the Bronx Bull, has lost his first fight.
That's Jake's fight! Come on, that's Jake's fight!
Jake won that fight!
Don't leave. Don't get outta the fuckin' ring. Stay here.
You won... let him go first. Stay in, I'm tellin' you.
La Motta floored Reeves seven times in the fight,
but La Motta still lost the fight.
Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake!
Help!
...on his fuckin' back, they pick up his arm, he's dead.
They tell him he won the fight. People went crazy.
That shit woulda never happened if Tommy was there takin' care of it.
He's gotta be with Tommy to fight in New York, to get a title shot.
He's gonna wind up punch-drunk, your brother.
- I know. - You know.
You gotta make him understand it's the best thing for everybody involved.
- I said I know. - You know,
but you gotta make him know, make him understand it.
Jesus Christ, you wanna stop?
When the fuck you gonna stop with that stuff?
I told ya, I understand everything.
He just wants to do things for himself.
- Hard to understand? - It's because he's got a head
- like concrete. - You make me laugh.
You think it's easy? Why don't you talk to him?
- You know what to say. - You know I can't talk to him.
- Why can't you talk to him? - 'Cause he don't like me.
Nobody likes you, you oughta be used to it.
They knew.
They knew who was the boss.
The judges didn't know. Who knows what happened with them?
The people knew.
You don't believe me, you thought I was over there foolin' around, huh?
You thought I was foolin' around, didn't ya? Tell me the truth.
I ain't doin' no foolin' around.
- That's in your mind. - Yeah, so what?
That championship belt on me, that's when I fool around.
Is it done?
No, it's not done.
Don't overcook it. You overcook it, it's no good.
It defeats its own purpose.
What are you doin'? I just said don't overcook it.
You're overcookin' it, bring it over.
- You want your steak? - Bring it over.
Bring it over!
It's like a piece of charcoal! Bring it over here!
- You want your steak? - Yeah, right now!
Good. There's your stupid steak.
- Can't wait for it to be done? - No, I can't wait.
Good. Okay? Happy?
- Happy? - That's all I want.
That's... there, no, more. There.
Botherin' me about a steak, huh? You're botherin' me about a steak?
I agree with you. He should be with Tommy.
If he's in a good mood, I'll talk to him. What the fuck you want me to do?
Tommy tells me every day to talk to you
and speak to Jake to straighten this thing out,
I'm gonna wind up in the middle.
You're in the middle? I'm his brother.
- He's got me fuckin' nuts. - You're his brother.
If you can't talk to him, who's gonna talk to him?
- I'll talk to him. - Do what you can, that's all.
- That's all I'm askin' you. - I'll see you tomorrow.
- Let me go up. - All right? Where you gonna be?
I'll be at the gym or the other joint, one of the two.
- I'll catch you by the gym. - All right. Sal?
Yeah?
Complain some more, I wanna hear.
- Complain? You call those carrots? - That's right.
- You call that food? - You ate 'em. Did you eat them?
You call that food? I got no choice!
- I'm sick of you already! - I got no choice!
- I can't believe you! - I got no choice!
You got no choice? Get away from me!
- Please! - Get in there. Get in there!
Get your hands off me, get away from me!
Fuck! I'm sick of you!
What's the matter with you, you animals?
- What? - Jack, come on!
- You animals! - Come on, huh?
This son of a bitch is callin' me an animal.
- Hey, you! - Come on, Jack.
I'm gonna get hold of that dog, and I'm gonna eat it for lunch!
You hear what I'm sayin'? You hear me, Larry?
- Larry? - Crazy animal!
Who's an animal? Your mother's an animal!
You son of a bitch!
You're gonna find your dog dead in the hallway tomorrow, ya bum.
- I can't take it! - The whole block,
- people could hear you. - I'll kill the whole family.
- Sit down, relax. - I can't take this anymore!
You break anything in there, I'm gonna kill ya!
I swear to God, I'm gonna come in there and kill ya.
Yeah, sure.
You wanna calm down?
Oh, fuck!
What'd I do?
Come on, honey, let's be friends.
- Truce, all right? - It's not all right!
You can't, I'm telling you...
you can't fuckin' eat and drink like an animal,
put up with this fuckin' brasciole here.
You can't do this. I'm tellin' ya.
Forget about the Reeves thing, you got a million other fights comin' up.
You just can't keep doin' this.
What's wrong?
Something's the matter, what's up?
You know what's botherin' me?
My hands.
Your hands? What about 'em?
I got these small hands. I got a little girl's hands.
I got 'em, too. What's the difference?
Know what that means?
No matter how big I get, no matter who I fight,
no matter what I do, I ain't never gonna fight Joe Louis.
That's right, he's a heavyweight, you're a middleweight.
I ain't never gonna get a chance to fight the best there is.
And you know somethin'? I'm better than them.
I ain't never gonna get a chance.
You're asking me what's wrong.
You're crazy to even think about somethin' like that.
He's a fuckin' heavyweight, you're a middleweight.
It's impossible, it'll never happen, so why go crazy thinkin' about it?
It's not normal.
Do me a favor.
- Yeah, what? - I want you to hit me in the face.
- What? - I want you to hit me in the face.
Forget about it.
I want you to hit me in the face, go ahead.
- Take your best shot. - Forget about it, I ain't doin' it.
We have fights all the time... are you worried now?
Hit me in the face. Go ahead.
- No. - What, are you afraid?
Afraid of what?
Come on, don't be a little faggot, hit me.
- I ain't a fag. - Take your best shot, go ahead.
Come on. You gotta be a real jerk, you want me to punch you in the face.
Did I not tell you just to do it? Now I'm tellin' you, you gotta do it.
I ain't hittin' ya.
I'm your older brother, Joey. I'm tellin' ya somethin'.
I know what you said. I ain't doin' it.
I don't care if you get mad, I ain't doin' it.
Fuckin' nut.
I'm not doin' it, I'm not gonna do it.
I don't have any gloves. What am I gonna hit you with, the table?
- I ain't doin' it. - Use that over there.
- What? - That's right, use that.
Wrap it around your hand! How many times I gotta tell you?
- Not too many more. - Go ahead.
You want me to hit you?
I want you to hit me...
... with everything you got. I want you to fuckin' lay me out, go ahead.
- You sure? - Yeah.
- Go ahead. - All right.
- Harder. - Yeah?
You throw a punch like you take it up the ass, come on.
Harder, harder.
- Harder. - That's hard, you fuck.
- What do you want? - Take it off.
- Take it off. - Come on, you wanna stop now?
- That's enough with that... - Take it off.
Come on.
- Come on. - Don't fuck around.
- What are you, a girl? - Oh, girl, huh?
I'm gonna smack you again, throw it again.
- That's enough. - Go ahead.
- I said that's enough! - Harder, harder.
No, your fuckin' cuts are opening and everything.
What are you tryin' to prove? What does it prove?
Hey, Vito.
Joey, what's what?
Jake, you're lookin' good.
How you doin'?
Don't stay here.
Joey.
Come here.
Yeah, he looks mad, huh?
Looks mad.
Spoke to him yesterday, I don't know.
You told 'em to come up here?
Answer me when I talk to you.
Yeah, why? I can't have my friends up here?
- I heard this fucker didn't win the fight. - Take it easy.
Don't ever bring 'em up here again, hear me?
Hear me? Come on.
- Come on! - They look like two fags over there.
We're gonna go, I'll call you tomorrow, huh?
Hey, Jake, watch you don't hurt yourself.
How's your wife? Is everything okay?
Anybody bothers you, let me know, okay?
Yeah. Yeah, wave. They're your friends.
What the fuck is wrong with you? You gotta make a fuckin' jerk outta me.
They only came up here 'cause Tommy told 'em to come up to try to help us.
What's the matter with you, help who? What's the matter with you?
How they gonna help me? What, by takin' my money?
Is that what youse talkin' about, takin' my money?
I'm here breakin' my ass, not them.
Don't ever bring 'em up here again, you hear me?
What are ya, a jerk there?
I'm a jerk? You're a fuckin' asshole.
What the fuck you hittin' me, huh?
Yeah, yeah, ya fuckin' hard-on, try this.
Maybe you can't, huh?
Ya fuck!
Come on, give me a Coke.
Hey, shove off. You gonna go to the dance?
Go to the dance?
- Who's that girl over there? - The one I was talkin' to?
- Yeah. - The blonde?
- Yeah. - Vickie, you mean.
- Where's she from? - She's from the neighborhood,
she's a neighborhood girl.
What's her last name?
Vickie, that's all I know. They call her Vickie.
She knows them?
She knows them, they know her, she comes to the pool every day.
Everybody knows each other... you know how that shit works.
- She go with them? - She don't go with nobody.
She's 15 years old, where the fuck's she gonna go?
Where ya gonna take her, the Copacabana?
I heard there was a girl that he went with
that was a very beautiful young girl, blonde.
- Yeah? - It's not her?
I doubt it very much.
What are you thinkin' about, anyway?
She ain't the kinda girl you just fuck and forget about.
Joey, how many times I gotta tell ya?
Why are you always cursin' when I'm talkin' to you?
Don't do it around me. Do it around your friends.
- It's that thing, just don't do it. - All right, she's...
The kinda girl you bang and forget about... she's not like that.
You gotta spend time with her, get involved.
You know, it's...
D'you bang her?
- No. - Tell me the truth.
I just told you the truth. I tell you the truth the first time,
you don't have to ask me again, I never do that.
I always tell you the truth. If I did it, you would know.
I took her out a couple of times.
You went with her? You didn't try to fuck her?
I try to fuck anything, you know that.
- She didn't go with you? - No, she didn't go for it.
- Naturally. - Naturally?
- She knew better. - What do you mean, she knew better?
She knew you were an animal,
she knew it was no good if you'd go with her.
Her reputation would be ruined.
I thought he was talkin' to you, Vickie.
- That's... - That's the same guy?
- Yeah, it's the same guy. - I gotta break his legs.
He was over here yesterday.
- He was here yesterday? - You missed him.
I was up to the house yesterday. Didn't know he was over here.
- You stay in there, I'll go find him. - No, I can catch him.
Your friends, they're in a huddle. Big business meeting.
Come by the pool, they sit around and talk.
Big deals. They make sure she can hear.
Hey, like the big man. Get the fuck outta here.
Where you goin', gettin' in the water?
Don't get your hair wet.
Big shot.
Get him alone in the back room, smack him around, no more big shot...
without his gun.
Yeah, real tough guys.
- They're all tough guys. - What are you thinkin' about?
Keep lookin'. Where the fuck you goin'? You're dead, you're married.
You're a married man, it's all over. Leave the young girls for me.
Big shot.
Let's get outta here. You gonna stay here all night?
We'll never get through.
Where the hell do you think you're goin' at this hour?
What are you, a cop? I'm goin' out. Business.
Fuckin' worm. You go out, I'm goin' out.
Do what you're gonna do, what do I care?
Run out, see if I care.
I'm not gonna be here when you get back!
Fuckin' bunch of guineas.
- You're always hangin' out together! - Why don't you stop already?
Why don't you fuckin' stop? You're not goin' on business.
- You're goin' to suck each other off! - Why don't you have some respect?
- The whole buildin' hears ya. - Suck him! Suck him, baby!
Hey, Larry! Now you got somethin' to talk about
with that fuckin' dog, and this one up there.
Fuckin' Jew cunt, why don't you hit her in the head with a bat?
Don't call her no names, she's still my wife.
- How much abuse you wanna take? - I hit her enough.
- What am I supposed to do? - Kill the fuck.
Go ahead! Just leave me here like a dog!
You and your fuckin' ass... you, too ya... go out!
- What's the matter with you? - What the fuck's the matter with you?
- You gotta leave me here? - You let the whole block hear you.
- What's the matter with you? - I could give a shit, ya fuckin' queer!
- Faggot! Go stick it up his ass! - What'd you say?
Oh! Beans!
Jack.
Beansy got a table in the back, he said we could sit with them.
Beansy who? Which Beansy?
- Huh? - Beansy who?
Beans, you know, he's one of the guys.
- You'll know him when you see him. - She'll be over there?
I don't know, but you could see from there, at least.
- Come on, let's go. - I don't wanna look too hard.
- Hello, Joe, how you doin'? - Beansy, what is it?
Thanks for the seats.
- Hi, Joey. - Hey, what's up? Hey.
Nothing. I got trouble with these two motherfuckin' greaseballs downstairs,
- they got me crazy. - Hello, Father, how ya doin'?
- Hey, Father, what is it? - Oh, ho, Father!
You wanna get laid? You sure?
- You sure? - Hey, no, no.
Father, where you goin'? Bless the table, give us a shot.
D'you put money in the basket this week?
- You see her right there? - I saw, I saw.
- Okay? - I saw.
- They're goin' with her. - Don't worry about them, go ahead.
Go ahead.
Get the fuck out, you greaseball bastard!
Get out! Get out!
You, too, get out.
Get outta here, ya fuckin' bum, ya!
- Rotten bastards! - Go back where you came from.
Hey, Vickie!
- Hi, Joey. - How you doin'?
- I'm all right, what are you doin'? - Nothin' much, what are you doin'?
- That your car? - No, it's my brother's.
D'you ever meet my brother?
- No, Is that him? - Yeah. Wanna meet him?
- All right. - Hey, Jack!
There.
Vickie, this is my brother Jake. He's gonna be the next champ.
Hi.
How you doin'?
Nice to meet you.
- Nice car. - You like that car?
Yeah. It's nice.
Where you from?
Around here.
You wanna go for a ride?
All right. Gotta give me a few minutes, I have to change, okay?
- All right? - All right.
- I'll be back in a little while - I'll be over there.
Okay.
Move over.
- I never played this game. - Go ahead.
It's the only way you're gonna learn. Here, I'll show you how to do it.
That's the way, that's right.
- Like this? - Yeah, that's right.
- Hit it? - Just hit it nice.
Hit the middle one.
You see it?
No.
What does that mean?
It means the game is over.
Come on, let's go.
Daddy?
Dad? Come on in.
Probably went shoppin' or somethin', let me see.
Yeah, he must have went shoppin'. Sit down.
- You want somethin' to eat? - No.
- You sure? - Mm-hmm.
Salute.
Why don't you sit over here? Sit a little closer.
You're so far away, like you're on the other side of the room.
Come here, come here.
Come here. Sit over here.
Come on, come up from there.
That's better.
No, thank you anyway.
Some water?
Wanna see the rest of the place?
All right.
I bought it for my father. I bought the building.
Oh, yeah?
- From fightin'? - Yeah.
What else?
This is the dining room.
That's a bird.
It was a bird. It's dead now, I think.
The restroom.
Sit down.
That's me and my brother. We were foolin' around.
I know.
You look good, though.
What are you smilin' about?
I don't know.
You know how beautiful you are?
Anybody ever tell you how beautiful you are?
Yeah, they tell you all the time.
Sugar Ray Robinson and Jake La Motta in Detroit
for their second fight.
The undefeated Sugar Ray defeated Jake
at Madison Square Garden last October.
You can see the contrast in their styles...
the speedy Ray Robinson up on his toes, the dancing master.
La Motta the brawler moves in flat-footed most of the time.
Now he's hurt Robinson.
La Motta coming at Robinson again,
both hands to the head, a left and a right to the jaw.
A hard left hand to the body thrown by La Motta.
Round 8, and it's anybody's fight at this point. 10-rounder.
La Motta drives both hands to the head, hurts Robinson again.
Hooks the left hand to the jaw, a right to the body.
Robinson comes back with a right on the nose.
La Motta drives him across the ring, a left and a right to the head.
A hard left hand to the body, and Robinson is driven out of the ring
for the first knockdown of his career.
This is the nearest Robinson has been to a loss.
The fight nears its end. La Motta has taken charge of the fight.
The undefeated Sugar Ray... his winning ways are in jeopardy.
La Motta coming at him again. La Motta, feigning a left hand.
After ten rounds,
Judge Rossi, 8-2, La Motta.
Judge Murphy, 7-3, La Motta.
La Motta has won the fight!
A unanimous decision for the Bronx Bull.
Jake La Motta handing Sugar Ray Robinson
his first loss as a professional, and Robinson doesn't like it.
With this stunning victory, La Motta broke what was considered
the impossible... the invincible Sugar Ray's record.
La Motta has proved himself a great fighter,
and he shouldn't be denied a shot at the middleweight crown.
You sure we should be doin' this?
Come here.
You said never to touch you before a fight.
Come here, before I give you a beatin'.
You said I couldn't. You've been good for two weeks.
Come here.
Touch my boo-boos.
"Boo-ba?"
Boo-boo. Give the boo-boo a kiss.
Make it better.
Take off my pants.
You know how to take off my pants?
Now take off the rest.
You made me promise not to get you excited.
Go ahead, do it.
Take off your panties.
I like the gym smell.
What?
I like the smell of the gym.
No, no, no, no. Enough, enough.
I can't do any more. If I do any more, I'll sink it.
I gotta fight Robinson, I can't fool around.
What are you doin'?
What are you doin'? What are you doin' to me?
Jake La Motta and Sugar Ray Robinson
meet for the third time.
These men are unique, becoming classic rivals.
These two men... fierce, powerful fighters,
dangerous... so much so that no other fighter will go near them.
And so, they fight each other, three weeks apart.
They've each won one,
and they'll probably fight again, the way it looks now.
They go to close quarters at the bell.
Round 7, with Sugar Ray well ahead on points,
La Motta may need a knockout.
The left hook to the jaw,
and Robinson is down for the second time in his career.
He was down in the last fight, too.
La Motta watches Sugar Ray take the count from the referee.
- Robinson trying to get up. - ...six... seven...
- eight... - He's up on his feet now,
and the referee is wiping off his gloves. He is stunned.
La Motta comes at him.
Despite being knocked down, Robinson is well ahead on points.
He hooks a left to the jaw, a left and a right to the head by Robinson.
Your attention, fans.
Judge Joe Lanahan
scores it 8-1, 1-even,
in favor of Sugar Ray Robinson!
Boo! Boo!
A big vote for Sugar Ray Robinson.
...of 6-2, and 2-even,
for the winner by unanimous decision,
Sugar Ray Robinson!
Cocksuckers! I'd like to fuckin'...
- For Christ's sake! - I'll kill those cocksuckers!
They only gave him that fuckin' decision
'cause he's goin' in the Army next week, that's the only reason.
I knocked him down, I don't know what else I gotta do.
- What the hell I gotta do? - You won and they robbed ya!
They're miserable, because their mothers take it up
the fuckin' ass, that's why!
I've done a lot of bad things, Joey. Maybe it's comin' back to me.
Who knows? I'm a jinx, maybe. Who the hell knows?
Forget about all that shit... this was your shot.
They robbed us! They out and out robbed us!
- It's Vickie, you wanna talk to her? - I don't wanna talk to nobody.
- Joey, take her home. - All right.
- You gonna be all right? - Yeah, I'll be all right.
You sure?
- Make sure she's all right. - All right.
Yeah, child. I am coming back and bash you on your head one more time.
Don't ever do that Janiro bullshit again,
no more deals like that, you hear what I'm sayin'?
- What are you talkin' about? - What am I talkin' about?
Look at that... 168 pounds.
- Stop eatin'. - What's with the smart answers?
I told ya I didn't wanna do it in the first place, didn't I?
No, you didn't say that.
You're the one that told me you could get down to 155 pounds.
Where'd I get it? Did I pull it out of the fuckin' air?
I don't know if I'm gonna make it down to 155.
I'm lucky I make it to 160.
And on top of that, you sign me for a fight at 155,
and If I don't make the 155, I lose $15, 000?
- That's right. - You're supposed to be a manager!
You're supposed to know what you're doin'.
- I did just what I wanted to do. - That's what I'm worried about, you...
- You want a title shot? - What are ya talkin' about?
- Do you want a title shot? - What am I, in a circus over here?
I ask him, he's got more sense about this. What are you doin'?
You been killin' yourself for three years now, right?
There's nobody's left for you to fight. Everybody's afraid to fight you.
Along comes this kid Janiro. He don't know any better.
He's a young kid, up and comin', he'll fight anybody.
Good, you fight him.
Bust his hole. Tear him apart. What are you worried about?
What's the biggest thing you got to worry about?
- I'm worried about the weight. - You're worried about the weight?
What we arguin' for? I just said the weight.
Let's say you lose because of your weight.
Are they gonna think you're not as tough as you were?
You're not the same fighter?
Good. They'll match you with all those guys
they were afraid to match you with you before.
What happens? You'll kill 'em. And they gotta give you a title shot.
- Bring me coffee, please. - Why? There's nobody else.
Nobody's left.
- Who they gonna give it to? - Coffee.
- In a minute. - You listenin' to me?
- Please, honey, bring me the coffee. - All right, just a minute.
- How long I gotta wait? - Are you listenin'?
Now let's say you win, you beat Janiro.
Which you definitely should beat him, right?
- Yeah. - Right?
- Yeah. - They still gotta give you
a shot at the title. You know why?
- Why? - 'Cause the same thing as before,
there's nobody left, there ain't nobody around.
They gotta give you the shot.
Ya understand? If you win, you win.
If you lose, you still win.
There's no way you can lose, and you do it on your own,
just the way you wanted to do it, without help from anybody.
Ya understand? Just get down to 155 pounds, ya fat bastard.
Stop eatin'. What's the problem? Stop eatin', that's all, you can do it.
You don't understand anything, do you understand that?
Joey's right, this Janiro is an up-and-coming fighter,
he's good-lookin', he's popular.
- You beat him now... - Excuse me, what do you mean,
- good-lookin'? - I'm not sayin' good-lookin',
- I'm sayin' popular. If you win... - But what were you just sayin'
- about good-lookin', popular? - I'm not sayin' anything.
- I'm just tellin' you Joey's right. - Are you an authority, or what?
- Nothin'... - Get outta here.
Get outta here. Take the baby and get outta here.
Everybody all of a sudden's an authority about this.
Where'd she find out he's good-lookin', first of all?
She didn't mean nothin'.
Who asked you?
You gonna start with me now?
When people are talkin', you don't interrupt.
It's none of your business, especially if it's my brother and his wife.
Ain't got nothin' to do with you.
Get outta here, go inside. Take the baby inside.
Come on. Let's leave the grouches here, okay?
- Come on. - Change her diapers, can't you see?
- She's gonna cry, she stinks. - You make her cry.
- I'm gonna make you cry. - Yeah. Mm-hmm. Come on.
- They're a couple of babies. - 155 pounds...
let's go to the training camp.
No distractions, no wives, no phone calls.
Nobody around to bother you. I'll write out your usual schedule,
- your usual diet... - Listen, I wanna ask you somethin'.
When I'm away, you ever notice anything funny goin' on with her?
- With who, Vickie? - Yeah.
Like what?
What do you think I mean?
No, I don't notice anything.
I want you to keep an eye on her, all right?
For what, Jack? She don't do anything wrong.
I want you to keep an eye on her when I'm away, all right?
You just start trouble for nothin', I'm tellin' ya, you're crackin' up.
I got a reason, right?
You and I both know, any woman, given the right time,
the right place, the right circumstances, they'll do anything, right?
I mean, anything's possible. All right?
- You're right. - You oughta know.
You're not wrong, but you're pickin' on this girl, 'cause I saw you before.
You're worried about your weight, you're gettin' aggravated,
and you tell her, "What are you... ? Go inside. Who asked ya?"
Botherin' her for that, you're gonna give her an excuse to go out.
- She was talkin' about a guy. - So?
So what? She was talkin' on your behalf, she wasn't...
On my behalf? She was talkin' about a pretty kid, sayin' he's good-lookin'.
What are you talkin' about?
So you make him ugly, what's the difference?
- That's why? - Never mind, just do it.
All right.
You know what you should do? Go inside and be nice to her.
Make up with her.
Tell her you're gonna take her out, we'll go out.
You wanna go out before you go away, don't you?
This way, you go away with a clear head.
You know you took her out,
you wined and dined her, you had a good time.
All right?
All right. Where do you wanna go?
- Well, "out" out, you know. - All right.
Listen, though, if you tell her now, pull her on the side.
Don't say nothin' in front of Lenore...
- 'cause I'm not takin' her. - It's on your head.
- All right. - We can go without her.
- Do what you're gonna do. - Oh, I am.
Come here.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen,
it's great to be back in the Copa Lounge.
What a great audience.
Come on, lady, laugh it up... I laughed when you come in.
But seriously speakin', folks, we have a special guest with us tonight.
I'd like to introduce the world's leading middleweight contender,
the Bronx Bull, the raging bull.
Let's hear it for the great Jake La Motta, ladies and gentlemen.
What's your name again?
- Janet. - Janet, sorry, yeah, just been...
It's, uh, toast time.
He hits me with a left hook... no hand, just a hook he had.
- Where you goin'? - Goin' to the bathroom.
Hey, Vickie.
- Hi. - Gee, you're lookin' great.
- Thanks. - Joe here?
Yeah, they're over there. Jake's here, too.
That's great. Listen, I'm over here
with Tommy and some of the old gang.
You get a chance, come over and have a drink.
See ya later.
- Hello, Jake, how are you? - How you doin'?
You're not drinkin', are ya?
- Joey, how are ya? - How you doin', Sal?
Look like you're havin' a ball over here.
I'm over there with Tommy Como.
Why don't you come over and have a drink?
Tommy's here? I didn't even see him come in.
Charlie Rocks, what are we gonna do here?
What you got? What's the odds?
I'll see you later, Joey.
Hey, that's some suit. He looks good, huh, Jack?
I thought that was my best joke.
Rita, Look who's here.
Hi, Vickie.
Hey, Vickie.
- Say hello to Tommy. - How are ya, honey?
Good to see ya. Say hello to Charlie.
- Sit down, have a drink. - I can't, I have to get back to Jake.
- I just came by to say hello. - All right, honey, thanks for comin' by.
- Not a bad kid, that Vickie, ya know. - She's with that fuckin' gorilla.
She must've caught a hundred beatin's off that guy.
- What took ya so long? - I went by Tommy's table to say hello.
I saw you say hello to them all. But what took ya so long?
Nothin', I said hello. I came back.
- What else did you say? - He asked me if I wanted a drink.
I said, "No, Jake and Joey are over there, " and I left.
What were you talkin' to Salvy for?
He asked me if Joey was there, I said, "He's over there."
Then he said, "Tommy's over there, why don't you go say hello?" And I did.
Are you interested in him?
No, why would I be interested in him?
You sure you're not interested in him?
Yeah.
In other words, you're not interested in him, but you could be interested
- in somebody? - Jake, don't start.
What do you gotta... ? Hey, shut up, or I'm gonna smack you in the face.
You embarrass me.
These are from Mr. Como.
Shall I take the...?
- What? - Should I take this?
- Are you finished? - I'm not through with it.
- Okay. - These are the jokes, folks.
I tell ya the truth, it's so... Hi, how are ya, you bald-headed fag?
- Hey, Joey. - Tommy, thanks for the drinks.
- Come on, any time. - Charlie, how are ya?
How you doin', Joey? How's everything?
- Where's Jake? - He's over there, he don't wanna come.
- If you call him, he'll come. - All right.
- I'll be right back. - Here he comes.
What is it? You don't call anybody anymore.
We never see ya anymore. For cryin' out loud.
You never come around anymore? You can't even make a call? What is it?
I'm busy, I'm goin' away fightin', I'm busy.
Busy, busy. Look at him takin' me seriously.
I'm only kiddin' you, what a fuckin' kid.
- That's the best fuckin' fighter around. - Hey, Jake.
- How you doin'? - Them mulignanes.
forget about it, they're all afraid to fight you.
- How you feelin', all right? - I'm all right.
- Good? Strong? - Strong, yeah. I'm doin' okay.
Then Janiro's gotta watch his ass, right?
I think he should.
Last three, four times, I won nothin' but money with the guy.
He's no piece of cake, that's a good fighter.
Very attractive guy. All the girls like him.
No marks, clean.
Jake, am I wrong? Did you gain a few pounds?
A few pounds. I'll knock it off right away, though, no problem.
Right off, right off.
Look, let me ask you somethin'. I'm just talkin' now, just talkin'.
I come to you, and I'm tellin' you that I'm gonna bet a lot of money on you
in this fight with Janiro, right?
Yeah?
What would you tell me? What could you say to me?
I would say bet everything you got.
- Everything? - Everything.
'Cause I'm gonna open his hole like this.
Excuse my French, girls.
- I'm gonna make him suffer. - What's wrong with this guy?
I'm gonna make his mother wish she never had him.
- Is this somethin' personal? - Make him into dog meat. What?
- Did he say somethin' in the papers? - No, he's a nice kid.
He's a pretty kid, too.
I don't know, I got a problem... if I should fuck him or fight him.
Must be crazy. Fuck him or fight him.
You're really liable to get fucked with this kid, watch out.
- By who? - Janiro.
You mean you want me to get him to fuck you?
- Me? - Yeah.
- No, I don't want him to fuck me. - I could do that easily.
How you gonna do that?
I'll get youse both in the ring and give youse both a fuckin' beatin',
and you both could fuck each other.
- I'll get all full of blood. - You're used to that.
Come on, drink up. That's ginger ale, Jake.
- Come on, salute. - Salute.
- Jake, good luck. - Salute. Good luck, Jake.
Hey, Vick.
- What? - You awake?
No.
- Can you hear me? - What?
You ever think of anybody else...
when we're in bed?
- What do you mean? - You know, when we make love.
No, nobody, I love you.
How come you said that thing about Janiro?
- What did I say? - You said he had a pretty face.
I never noticed his face.
How come you said that, then?
I don't even know what I said. I don't even know what he looks like.
Go to sleep.
- He ain't pretty no more. - He really messed him up.
And the winner by unanimous decision...
... in ten rounds, Jake La Motta!
Give me a little piece of ice, just a sliver, just for my tongue.
- No water! - Come on, I'm dyin'.
Fuckin' hard-on.
Four pounds.
Keep workin'. Cut the bullshit.
I saw him fight with Janiro, I couldn't believe it...
destroyed this guy, it was absolutely incredible.
He knocked his nose from one side of his face to the other.
- You've gotta be kiddin'. - Fuckin' thing was hangin' off.
Who you fightin' next? Can you tell me?
I don't know. You never know these things...
From all I've seen, they gotta give him that title shot.
Jackie Curtie, Joey.
- You should know each other. - Hi, Joey.
Pleasure... heard a lot of nice things about you.
We're gonna get the title shot, too.
I'm sure. I like your brother. Made a lot of money on him.
Probably more than he did, that's for sure.
Made some nice cabbage on the Oscar Jackson fight.
Whatever happened to Oscar?
- Anybody see him anymore? - He's punchy, he probably died.
Who the fuck cares?
- Make yourselves comfortable. - It's a beautiful table.
- The worst table in the house. - And he's complainin'.
It's a beautiful table.
He's workin' downtown, big building... workin' an elevator.
Happened to be there the other day.
I'm not Italian, I don't care.
- Took me right up. - Hey, that Oscar's always
a stand-up guy, Joey, he did you a lot of good.
Gave your brother a hell of a fight, too.
Yeah, Mickey? Cutty Sark and water.
Excuse me one minute, fellas.
- I'll be right back. - Come back, Joey.
Come on back. Okay.
- Hey. - Hey.
Hey, Joe.
- Hey, Joey. - Look at how he's lookin' at us.
- Something's happening. - She's having a problem.
- You're worried about it? - I'm just sittin' there havin' a drink!
- Shut up. Keep your mouth shut. - Both of youse are the same.
I feel like I'm a prisoner.
I can't walk, I look at somebody the wrong way, I get smacked.
You think you're right or somethin', the way you're fuckin' yellin'?
- I am right. - You're wrong.
I am right. I'm tired of having to turn around
and havin' both of youse up my ass all the time.
- Shut up. - No.
- Don't make me... - I'm tired of listenin' to you
- and your brother. I'm not wrong. - Don't make me get nuts in this place.
What am I supposed to do?
I'm 20 years old, I gotta go home and sleep by myself every night?
- What the fuck did you marry him for? - 'Cause I love him.
- You do? - Yeah, I love him.
What am I supposed to do? This guy don't even wanna fuck me.
He's just been a contender too long.
He'll be all right as soon as he gets his shot, and then everything'll be okay.
You won't have to go fuckin' runnin' around when he does.
Jake is never gonna be champ. Too many people hate him.
- And you're drinking with them! - And I'm gonna finish my drink
- and I'm gonna have a good time. - Get your stuff.
I said you ain't stayin' here.
- Get your stuff. - I'm stayin'.
You're making an asshole out of my brother, get your stuff.
- Come on, relax. - Shut up.
Mind your fuckin' business and shut up.
- You're taking this all wrong. - I said shut up, didn't I?
What's the matter with you? There's nothin' goin' on here.
This is innocent. We're only having a few drinks.
- Relax, no problem. - Come on, you know better than that.
- All right. Let's all calm down. - Just relax, come on.
- We've been friends a long time. - I'm just upset.
- It's my brother's wife... - There's nothing goin' on over here.
I'm sorry, I really am.
We're friends, we can straighten this...
Right? Nothing going on?
Nothing going on? Ya dirty cocksucker!
- Fuckin' hard-on! - Get off! Get him off!
I'll bite your fuckin' head off, ya cocksucker!
Get outta here, Joey! What the fuck are you doin'?
- Easy, easy! Come on! - Get your hands off me!
- Come on! - Come on!
Fuckin' cunt.
Get out! Get outta the way!
Oh, scumbag! I'm gonna suck your fuckin' eyes out!
Hey, you fuckin'... what are you, nuts?
Don't mention Tommy.
You do what you do, and we do what we gotta do.
- Don't mention no names. - No, you're wrong, Joe.
He's wrong. No fuckin' trouble in the joint.
I said get outta here, ya fuckin' mamone!
Get back there, ya fuck, ya!
Take it easy, people. Come on, now, take it easy.
You've had it, you rat bastard!
You guys have a lot of years between you,
and you've done a lot of things together.
I understand, Joey, it was your brother's wife.
But you don't raise your hands,
you don't create a scene like that in a place like that.
Now, we've heard everybody's point of view here,
and we're gonna forget about it.
I shouldn't forget about it, but we're gonna forget about it.
Right?
What I want you to do now, you two guys,
I want you to shake hands, forget this whole thing,
and no grudges.
That's the most important thing... no grudges.
Now, come on, shake hands.
It's all right with me if it's all right with you.
All right?
I only wish this thing never happened.
We all wish it never happened.
Right? You'll get over it.
Salvy, let me talk with him alone a minute.
Yeah, all right.
I'll see you Monday, Tuesday or somethin', all right?
I'm sorry, I forgot all about it.
What are you, fucking nuts? You're killin' me.
Aside from everything else, is the family all right?
Yeah, they're fine. Everybody's fine.
What is it with you? You can't talk?
- I'm talkin', what do you mean? - I know.
Why have you got this funny attitude? I can't figure you out.
What is it with all the quick answers? "Yeah, they're all right. Yeah."
You wanna get outta here fast or something?
No, it's nothin' like that.
It's just all the aggravation and everything and...
all the fights and all.
Listen to me. Now, Jake...
the guy's become an embarrassment.
He's embarrassin' me with certain people,
and I'm lookin' very bad.
I can't deliver a kid from my own goddamn neighborhood.
What is it with him?
Why does he have to make it so hard on himself?
He comes to me, I make it easier for him.
The man's got a head of rock.
You know, it's hard to explain, Tommy, he's...
Jack respects you.
I mean, he don't even say hello to anybody.
You he talks to, he likes you.
It's just that when he gets somethin' on his mind,
he's got a hard head, he likes to do things his own way.
Jesus Christ could come off the cross sometimes,
he don't give a fuck, he's gonna do what he wants to do,
he wants to make it on his own. He thinks he can make it on his own.
Make it on his own.
He thinks he's gonna walk in there and become champion on his own?
- He's crazy. You know he's nuts. - Yeah, he's crazy.
And he's got no respect for nobody, he doesn't listen to nobody.
That's not crazy.
- He respects you, though. - He doesn't respect anybody.
Now, you do this for me, you understand?
You tell him I don't care how colorful he is, how great he is.
He could beat all the Sugar Ray Robinsons
and the Tony Janiros in the world.
But he ain't gonna get a shot at that title, not without us, he ain't.
Now, you're a smart kid.
You go to him, you tell him...
Son of a bitch.
Twenty dollar shoe here.
Aren't you gonna ask me what happened?
What's the matter?
- What's wrong? - I remember when I met her here.
- Who? - Vickie.
Why, what's the matter? What'd she do now?
I know she's doin' somethin', I just wanna catch her once.
Just once.
Hey, Jack. Wanna do yourself a favor?
Bust her fuckin' hole, throw her out.
Either that, or live with her and let her ruin your life,
'cause that's what's happenin'.
How much could you take? How much shit could you take?
So, what'd that guy say?
He gave me the old "good news, bad news" routine.
The good news is
you're gonna get the shot at the title.
The bad news is they want you to do the old flip-flop for them.
- So, what else is new? - What'd you expect?
You didn't know that was comin'?
You win some, you lose some.
This one, we're losin'.
Billy Fox.
173 and 3/4 pounds.
- Jake La Motta. 167... - I guess you've heard by now
a lot of the stuff that's goin' around, a lot of rumors.
Matter of fact, a short time ago you were a big favorite,
and all of a sudden, you're a 12-5 underdog,
and people are talkin', it's as simple as that.
- That's funny, I never heard anything. - It's out there, though,
and It's not good.
As a matter of fact, the bets are off on this one.
Nothin' goin' in this one.
Matter of fact, smart money is sayin' that you're getting ready to hit the tank.
- That's bullshit. - Yeah, that's bullshit.
You got any money you wanna bet?
- Come on. - I'll take the action, go ahead.
You bet it on Fox, 'cause I'm gonna win.
There's no way I'm goin' down. I don't go down for nobody.
- That's what I wanted to hear. - I want you to know that.
- All right. - All right, Colonel.
Okay, that's it.
You came down here just for that nonsense?
- That was it? - That was it.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the Madison Square Garden
feature attraction.
- In this corner, weighing 175 pounds... - Commissioner, how about a picture?
Fellas, can we get a picture over here?
...the undefeated Billy Fox.
Hi, Steve. Your brother got out of the hospital?
- They think it's all right. - Did he get out? Good.
- Charlie, let me sit over there. - Yeah, sure.
Tommy, what's the matter? Everything's all right?
It's all right, yeah.
Touch gloves now, come out boxing.
Five seconds, Alex.
Come on, stand... come on, stand up!
What the fuck you doin'? Hit me, ya fuckin' bum, come on.
Come on.
What are you doin', Jake? Come on, box him!
What the fuck's the matter with you?
What do you think you're doin' out there?
- Huh? - Little slow, that's all.
- What are you doin' out there? - Take it easy, he'll be all right.
He's a little slow. He'll make it up, what are ya worried about?
Goddamn it. Come on, pick it up a little, Jake, I'm sorry.
Come on, Jake, I got some money on ya!
- Tank job! - Hit him back, ya bum!
- Come on. - Hit him back!
You fuckin' bum! You're takin' a dive in the fourth?
Pocket your dirty money!
Aw, you phony bastard! That's a fix!
We're stoppin' the fight!
What the fuck are you waitin' for to stop the fight, ya jerk?
And you standin' there.
- Fuckin' go down, will ya? - The referee stops this bout
at 2:23 of the fourth round.
The winner by technical knockout,
and still undefeated,
Billy Fox!
What'd I do?
Don't fight anymore.
It's a free country, don't fight anymore.
Aw, what'd I do? What'd I do?
What'd I do?
- Get outta here! - Jake has an interview...
It's all right, Jake. It's all right.
Why did I do it? Why?
They got some balls, some balls.
I take the dive. What more do they want?
They want me to go down, too?
I ain't goin' down. I ain't goin' down for nobody.
Why don't you do me a favor? Just put your hands up.
I wanna show you somethin'. Put your hands up.
- What the fuck is so hard about that? - Hey, you don't understand.
I had to fight a bum. He's a bum.
I fought the guy, I tapped him like that, all of a sudden he's like this
all over the place, what am I gonna do?
You don't have to fuckin' pick him up and help him.
What am I gonna do? If I don't pick him up,
then what am I gonna do? I'm gonna be in worse trouble.
I don't know.
"Purse was withheld... " look at this... "Purse was withheld pending
D.A.'s probe." Look at that.
Look how they make me look.
Like a bum, like a mammalucco.
A what?
Like the mammalucco of the year.
Tommy ain't gonna forget us.
You're gonna get your shot, as long as he don't die.
- As long as who don't die? - Tommy.
What are you talkin' about?
In other words, Tommy ain't gonna forget ya,
you're gonna get your shot if he don't die.
- Gotta make sure the guy stays alive. - He got a disease or somethin'?
No, I'm just sayin', I'm kiddin', like.
What's wrong with him? Is somethin' wrong with him?
There ain't nothin' wrong with him, that's the only way you wouldn't get it
- is if he dies, he won't be able to... - What are you talkin' like that for?
What do you want me to do? It's an outdoor arena.
What do you wanna do, fight in the rain? It's a stadium.
You waited this long, you can wait longer.
You wanna wait 24 hours? I don't wanna wait no 24 hours.
I don't either, but we gotta, so we'll wait. Hello?
- You guys wanna stop now? - Get off the phone with them.
Why do you give them the satisfaction?
- Get off the phone with them! - He don't wanna talk to nobody.
How many times do we have to tell ya? You hear him yellin'?
There's enough confusion up here. Please, don't call.
No comment. Right. Thank you. Bye!
Pains in the asses, I don't believe them.
Why do you give them the satisfaction? Why don't you just hang up on 'em?
- That's all. - I'm gonna get somethin' to eat.
- What do you want to eat? - I don't want nothin'.
I don't want nothin'.
Eat somethin', you gotta eat somethin'.
You can't go without eatin'. Eat a steak.
You chew it, you spit it out, you'll still make the weight tomorrow.
You're worried about that?
I'll order a steak. At least if you want it, it's here.
You don't want it, do whatever you want with it.
- Go ahead. - Vickie, what do you want?
Order me a piece of cake.
That's all you want is a piece of cake?
Why don't you get a cheeseburger, French fries? It's better for you.
- It's like a whole meal. - Yeah, that's good.
That's good, order me one of those.
Wait a minute, what do you want to eat?
Since when did you order one of those?
- That's what I want. - It's a free country.
You order what you want. Don't let nobody influence you.
I'm not tellin' her what to eat, I was just suggesting.
What are you tellin' her what to ask for?
I'm not tellin' her... personally, I don't give a fuck what she eats.
What were you tellin' her that for?
Order me a cheeseburger.
Just order her a cheeseburger, that's all.
What the f... ?
What are you guys doin' so long? How long does this thing take to do?
Forty seconds.
Forty seconds is no good. You gotta do it in 30 seconds.
If we gotta stitch him up, that's how much time.
Ya up?
- What? - Somebody's here to see ya.
- Hey, Jack. - Hey, Tommy, how you doin'?
How are you?
Say hello to Charlie. Charlie!
- Jake, how are ya? Lots of luck. - Hello, Charlie, good to see you.
Thank you.
- How you feeling? - I'm feelin' all right, thank you.
- Are you feeling good? - I feel as good as I'm gonna feel.
I gotta get in there and fight, then I'll know how I'm gonna feel.
All right. We just come by to wish you luck and all that.
- Thanks. - You need anything?
- No. - You sure, nothing?
No, thank you, Tommy.
All right. Take care, good luck.
- God bless ya. - All right, thank you.
- You'll be all right. - Yeah, I'll be all right.
See you later, everybody.
- Vickie, good-bye. - Tommy, wait.
We really appreciate your comin', I want you to know that.
It was really nice of you. I appreciate it.
- Come on, Joey, anytime. - A time like this is very important to him.
- Anytime. - I just wanted to say good-bye.
So long, honey. I want you to take good care of that guy, all right?
- I'll take care of him. - Joey, any little thing,
I want you to call me. He's very nervous. Ba-boom, call.
Good-bye, honey.
Would you look at that face? What a face.
Can you believe that girl?
Look at that beauty. Just as beautiful as ever.
- The least little thing, all right? - Bye-bye, Tommy.
- So long, everybody. - So long, Tommy.
Hey! Come here.
Come here a minute.
What was all that about?
All what?
You know what I'm talkin' about. What was that all about?
- With him. - Nothin', I just said good-bye.
All of a sudden you're so friendly with him?
- I just said good-bye. - You don't do that.
You say hello, you say good-bye, that's all, ya hear?
- I hear. - Hey!
You hear what I said? You don't ever have any disrespect for me.
You hear what I said?
- Yeah, I hear. - All right. Go in there.
- Come here. - Why don't you stop that?
Shut up, you! Shut up!
Shut up! I'll fuckin' take care of you later!
Shut up!
Disgusted with the two of youse.
Get to youse later.
I'm the boss, I'm the boss...
Hit the fuckin' thing, come on!
All right, let's go.
Good luck, Jake!
For the Middleweight Championship of the World, 15 rounds.
In this corner, the very worthy challenger,
weighing in at 158 1/4 pounds,
the Bronx Bull, Jake La Motta!
Shake hands, come out fighting at the bell.
Kill him!
Pressure, pressure, pressure!
Now finish him off. He's all stupiada. you got him.
Come on, Jake!
Blow on him, he'll fuckin' fall right over for ya.
Look at him. Do you feel all right?
- No way, huh? - Can't continue?
Hey, Commissioner? Come on in, I'm gonna stop the fight.
Yeah, you did it, Jake!
Ladies and gentlemen, may I have your attention, please?
Cerdan, unable to continue, the referee stops the fight.
And the winner by a technical knockout
in the tenth round,
and the new Middleweight Champion of the World,
the Bronx Bull, Jake La Motta!
Jake! Jake! Jake! Jake!
Don't shake that. Don't shake it like that, I'm tellin' ya.
It's the worst thing you could do.
Oh, you're home.
- Hi, Vick. - Hi, Joe.
- Hello. - Hi. Where were ya?
I went out. What's the matter?
Television won't work.
Where'd you go?
Went out, went shoppin'. Went to my sister's. You know.
What's the matter with you? What's with this kissin' on the mouth?
I just said hello. Can't I kiss my sister-in-law?
Isn't the cheek good enough for you?
Come on, huh?
I don't even kiss Mom on the mouth the way you kiss her.
All of a sudden, you're like a Romeo.
You're not supposed to kiss your mother on the mouth.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
- How's that? - That looks like somethin'.
Get back, I can't see nothin' with your stomach in the way.
What are you givin' me dirty looks for?
Supposed to be a champion, ya eat like there's no tomorrow.
That's it, go ahead... forget how long it took you
to get to the title, all the years, the hard work.
You forgot. You're gonna defend it next month, keep eatin'.
Give me dirty looks like I don't know what I'm talkin' about.
What happened with you and Salvy at the Copa that time?
- When? - When you gave him a beatin'.
You mean when I caught his head in the taxicab door,
and was bangin' it, smacked him with a glass?
- Yeah. - I told you about that.
- Didn't I? - No.
- I never told you? - No, you never told me.
It was no big thing, anyway.
I smacked him in the mouth, he was drunk, he started some shit.
Had to go downtown, straighten it all out with Tommy.
It's all forgotten about, supposedly, anyway.
How come you never told me about it?
It didn't have anything to do with you.
- Had nothin' to do with me? - No.
Who'd it have somethin' to do with... Vickie?
I just explained the whole thing to you, didn't I?
- Yeah. - It was between me and Salvy.
If it had anything to do with you and Vickie, I woulda told you about it.
That's not what I heard, Joe.
What do you mean, that's not what you heard?
- That's not what I heard. - What'd you hear?
I heard some things.
- You heard about me and Salvy... - I heard things, Joey.
You heard that I cracked Salvy all around, what'd you hear?
- I heard things. - What things you heard?
I heard some things.
You heard things. You wanna worry? Don't start that shit.
You know what you should worry about?
Worry you got this title fight next month. That's what you should worry about.
Do that.
Christ!
- Did Salvy fuck Vickie? - What?
Did Salvy fuck Vickie?
Hey, Jack, don't start your shit.
- No, really, don't start. - Joey, I asked ya.
- Didn't I ask ya to keep an eye on her? - And I did keep an eye on her.
Then how come ya gave him a beatin'?
I told you that. I told you what that was all about.
Didn't have nothin' to do with you.
- He thinks he's a wiseguy... - Joey, don't lie to me.
- I'm not lyin'. - What do I look like to you?
Hey, I'm your brother.
You're supposed to believe me. Don't you trust me?
- No, I don't. - You don't? That's nice.
I don't trust you when it comes to her. I don't trust nobody.
- Tell me what happened. - I told you exactly what happened.
He got out of line, I slapped him around.
Tommy straightened it all out, and it's all over.
You give me that look, Joey.
I gotta accept your answer, you know?
But I'm tellin' ya now, if I hear anything,
I swear on our mother, I'm gonna kill somebody.
- I'm gonna kill somebody. - Well, go ahead and kill everybody!
You're the tough guy, go kill people.
Kill Vickie, kill Salvy, kill Tommy Como,
kill me, while you're at it, what do I care?
You're killin' yourself, the way you eat, ya fat fuck!
- Look at ya! - What do you mean?
I don't understand, what do you mean, kill you?
Me, kill me! Start here! Kill me first, do me a fuckin' favor!
'Cause you're drivin' me crazy!
You're a killer, you're a big shot. Just kill, you're a killer.
Excuse me, what do you mean by you, though?
So? What does that mean? Don't mean nothin'.
Even you don't know what you meant by you.
- Don't mean nothin'. - Joey, that meant somethin'.
You mentioned Tommy, Salvy, you mentioned you...
you included you with them.
You coulda said anybody, but you said you and them.
You really let this girl ruin your life, look at ya.
She really did some job on ya, ya know how fuckin' nuts you are?
- Look what she did to you! - You fuck my wife?
- What? - You fuck my wife?
How could you ask me a question like that?
How could you ask me? I'm your brother.
You ask me that?
Where do you get your balls big enough to ask me that?
Just tell me.
I'm not answerin' that.
I'm not gonna answer that, it's stupid.
You're very smart, Joey.
You're givin' me all these answers, but you ain't givin' me the right answer.
I'm gonna ask ya again.
Did you or did you not?
I'm not gonna answer.
That's a sick question, you're a sick fuck,
and I'm not that sick that I'm gonna answer it.
I'm not tellin' ya anything. I'm gonna leave.
If Lenore calls, tell her I went home. I'm not stayin' in this nuthouse with ya.
You're a sick bastard... I feel sorry for ya, I really do.
You know what you should do?
Try a little more fuckin' and a little less eatin'.
You won't have troubles upstairs in your bedroom,
and you won't pick it out on me and everybody else.
Ya understand, ya fuckin' wacko? You're crackin' up.
Fuckin' screwball, ya.
Where were ya?
I was at my sister's.
Where'd you go after that?
- To the movies. - Yeah, what'd you see?
Father of the Bride.
How come you didn't tell me about the Copa?
- Tell you what about it? - You know.
How come you didn't tell me about it?
Why didn't you tell me about it, huh?
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
Why didn't you tell me? Did you fuck my brother?
- Get off me, you fat pig! - Did you? Did you?
- Huh? - No!
Open the door.
- Get away! - Come on, open the door.
- I wanna talk to you. - Get away from me, you're sick!
I just wanna ask you one thing. Why'd you fuck Joey?
- Get away! - Open the door.
No.
Why'd you do it? Why'd you do it, huh?
I didn't do anything!
- Why did you fuck them? - Do what? I didn't do anything!
I fucked all of 'em!
- What do you want me to say? - What do you mean, who'd you fuck?
I fucked all of 'em... Tommy, Salvy, your brother, all of 'em!
I sucked your brother's cock! What do you want me to say?
- You sucked his cock? - I sucked his cock,
and everybody else on the fuckin' street.
What do you want? You're nothin' but a fat pig, selfish fool!
Forget fuckin' with you!
His fuckin' cock's bigger than yours, too!
Where you goin'?
Where are you goin', you bastard?
You sick animal! Where you goin'?
Let me go! Get off of me, ya piece of shit!
If I see you put your hands in that plate one more time,
I'm gonna stab you with this knife, ya hear me?
I told ya, keep your hands outta the plate!
Why can't we eat in peace around here? Just relax.
Do I have to eat like you? Like a gavone, like...
Jack! Jack! What's the matter with you?
Ya fucked my wife, huh?
Get off of him!
- I'll kill ya! I'll kill ya! - Stop it, he didn't do it!
Call the police!
I'll fuckin' kill ya!
Get out!
Don't leave, honey, please.
Honey, look... I'm a bum without you and the kids, don't go.
Just...
Less than a minute to go, and La Motta is losing the title
that he won from the gallant Marcel Cerdan.
After the tragic plane crash that took Cerdan's life.
Laurent Dauthuille vowed to bring the title back to France.
Tonight, he only has to last this fifteenth round
to be crowned the new Middleweight Champion.
La Motta is taking terrible punishment on the ropes as Dauthuille bangs him
with lefts and rights to the head. Another left, another right to the jaw.
La Motta turns around, he's been playing possum!
He's got Dauthuille hurt! He rips a right hand to the body,
two left hooks to the jaw, another left and a right to the head!
Dauthuille is reeling around the ring!
The tide has turned, no question about it!
And he wobbles into the ropes and goes down!
Dauthuille is down, and referee Lou Handler comes over
and starts the count. He's trying to get up.
Six... seven...
He'll never make it. Nine... ten!
You're out!
It is all over!
He is knocked out, and Jake La Motta,
with 13 seconds left to go in the final round,
has made one of the most remarkable comebacks
- in all boxing history. - Jake La Motta!
Come on.
Just tell him you're sorry, you miss him.
He's your brother, you have to talk to him sooner or later.
I'll dial him for you, then you talk to him.
Just tell him you're sorry, then you can say whatever you want.
Go ahead.
Hey, champ... like to ask you a few questions.
- Not now. - I been waitin' an hour for you.
- Excuse me, my wife is... - There's a great angle here...
Don't bother me, please. Get outta here.
Come on. All right, champ?
- You're a great guy. - I asked you nice, will ya... ?
Hello?
Salvy, this ain't funny anymore.
Is that you?
I know somebody's there. I can hear you breathin'.
You listenin'?
Your mother sucks fuckin' big fuckin' elephant dicks.
You got that?
The fight of the year.
The next time that friendly bartender says, "What'll you have?"
give him that answer the whole world gives, "Pabst Blue Ribbon."
Those punches by La Motta explain themselves.
They fought five times between 1942 and 1945.
It has so far been a blazing bout for the Middleweight Championship.
In that great action by La Motta, he couldn't score the big one.
That's it, that was his last shot.
Round number 13, the hard-luck number.
There's the buzzer,
and I think you know both the boys.
Robinson hurting La Motta, he's hurting him now.
He has La Motta on queer street, holding on.
Certainly, that was one of the most damaging evidences
of punching that you have seen in recent years.
Come on! Come on.
- What are you standin' there for? - Robinson, apparently tired,
punched with a "fare thee well, " and rocked Jake La Motta
- right to his heels. - Come on, Ray, come on!
These are clean, whistling shots.
How he can survive them, nobody knows.
No man can endure this pummeling!
The fight is stopped on...
the signal to Frankie Sikora.
Row after row after row from the ring,
the crowd is standing and cheering,
as he just cannonaded Jake La Motta
- into a death defeat. - Hey, Ray.
And when I say that, I mean Jake wouldn't want to quit.
- He wanted to go. - Hey, Ray.
Never went down, Ray.
You never got me down, Ray.
Ya hear me?
Never got me down.
Yeah? See, look?
And in the thirteenth round, the hard-luck round,
the championship of the world has changed hands.
And there you see it...
a champion gone down to defeat.
And so, now we wait for the announcement
from Eddie Flint, the ring announcer.
Then we'll get up in the ring, join with the radio audience
throughout the world,
and have a brief interview with Ray Robinson.
Now we're waiting for the time to be announced.
And it is being handed between the commissioner and Eddie Flint.
The fight was stopped on a signal from Joe Tryner...
Attention, ladies and gentlemen!
The winner by a technical knockout in two minutes and four seconds
of the thirteenth round,
and the new World's Middleweight Boxing Champion,
Sugar Ray Robinson!
Why are you pulling out of Wednesday's fight?
It's over for me... boxing's over for me.
I'm through.
I'm tired of worryin' about weight.
That's all I used to think about was weight, weight, weight.
After a while, you realize there are other things in life.
I'm very grateful. Boxing's been good to me.
I got a nice house, I got three great kids.
I got a wonderful, beautiful wife. What more could I ask for?
- Hey, what's your name? - Bob.
Take a picture, Bob.
Let him take a picture of ya, honey... for us.
Go ahead, smile.
Thank you, Bob.
Take a picture of all of us. Jackie, come here, sit over here.
All right, everybody, smile. Smile.
Mrs. La Motta, how do you feel about Jake's retirement?
I think it's great.
He picked the right time to stop fightin'.
He's home with us all the time now.
- It's really good. - You know what? You through?
- Excuse me, you through? - Yeah.
I just bought a club on Collins Avenue.
It's a bar, package store, everything. Guess what I'm gonna call it?
I don't know.
- What are you gonna call it? - Take a guess.
All right, shut up. Enough, enough.
Thank you.
Just wanted to see what the microphone
on a sexy girl sounds like.
See how that sounds.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
I haven't seen so many losers since my last fight
at Madison Square Garden.
Okay, honey.
Thank you, doll.
- Isn't that somethin'? - Bring us another drink.
- Salute. - Salute.
Look at this terrific girl.
She's the kinda girl you wanna bring home to your father,
especially if he's a degenerate.
Did I say that?
Nah, seriously, folks, it's a thrill to be standing here
before all you wonderful people tonight.
In fact, it's a thrill to be standing.
If you believe it's a thrill to be standin' before you wonderful people, then...
you're all full of shit.
By the way, me and my wife Vickie's gettin' married.
What am I talkin' about? I'm out of it.
Is she here? She's not here.
Vickie? Nah, she's not here.
By the way, me and my wife Vickie's gonna celebrate...
it's a little different... our 11th wedding anniversary.
Thank you.
That reminds me about two friends of mine.
One was married, one was single.
The married guy tells the single guy,
"What's the matter with you?
"What's the matter with you? Look at me, and look at you.
And look at me, and look at you."
Let me get on with it.
"When I come home at night, my wife's at the door
"with a tall drink in her hand.
"Then she gives me a nice hot bath,
"then she gives me a nice rubdown,
"then she makes passionate love to me,
"and then she makes me a nice dinner.
What more could you ask for? You oughta try that."
The other friend says, "Hey, that sounds great."
What time does your wife get home?"
I know I'm no Olivier, but if he fought Sugar Ray,
he would say
that the thing ain't the ring,
it's the play.
So give me a stage
where this bull here can rage,
and though I can fight,
I'd much rather hear myself recite.
That's entertainment!
Jake, how have you been?
Hey! You were just great.
It's a good thing Sugar Ray wasn't here tonight, huh?
- He told that joke last week. - Come on!
He repeats himself, gettin' a little senile.
I'd like you to meet State's Attorney Bronson.
- How are ya? Nice to meet you. - And his wife.
- Nice to meet you. - You shouldn't be here this week.
It's next week we got the shakedown payments, right?
It's good seein' you.
That is a joke, right?
It's a joke... only you know if it's a joke.
He's just kidding, right?
All right, we'll talk about it later.
- This is your wife? - Yes, Mrs. Bronson.
Very pretty lady. Charmed to meet you.
- Thank you. - He's really a nice guy.
You can take a joke, can't you, doll?
- I'm sorry. - It's all right.
Hey, Carlo? Carlo!
Give 'em another drink. Somethin' happened over here.
- Darling, Linda, come here. - Where's your wife?
- My wife? - Yeah, why isn't she here?
What's it to you? You think I'm gonna bring her around here,
- let you bums get involved with her? - Come on!
Especially the State's Attorney over here?
He comes here a lot, darling, watch him.
He knows I'm only kiddin'.
- Thank you. - Keep an eye on him.
What's the problem?
There's really not a problem.
She doesn't look 21, so I just had to ask for some I.D.
- How old are you, honey? - Twenty-one.
- Twenty-one? - Mm-hmm.
Can you prove that you're 21?
- Mm-hmm. - Prove it to me.
Any girl that can kiss like that can drink at my joint anytime.
What about you? How old are you?
- Twenty-one. - Can you prove that you're 21?
- Yes. - Would you prove it to me?
Come here.
She's 21, too?
She has convinced me that she's 21, too.
- Watch it while I'm pouring. - Your wife's outside.
- She's waitin' for you. - Why don't ya tell me a little louder?
There.
Come on, Jake.
Lonely nights
I'm so lonely
Please come home
You great big lump of sugar
I miss you so much
Please come home
Lonely nights
It was a busy night last night.
- Everything all right? - I'm leaving you, Jake.
- What else is new? - No. I mean it this time.
I didn't wanna tell you till I had everything worked out.
- Move over. - Why?
- So you can put your hands on me? - Open the door.
Come on, honey, open the door.
I got a lawyer, we're gettin' a divorce
and I'm gettin' custody of the kids.
- Let me in for a minute. - No, I already made up my mind.
I'm leavin'. That's it.
Kids are gonna be with me, and if you show your face around,
I'm gonna call the cops on you.
- All right? That's it. - Don't act that way, honey.
Come on, champ. Come on, wake up.
Wake up, champ.
What's up?
- We're from the D.A. - Yeah, I know where you're from.
- They wanna talk with you. - Youse all look the same to me.
- What's the difference? - They wanna talk with you.
- About what? - I don't know, I don't run the joint.
- They just told me to bring you in. - But what do youse want?
For what?
Do you recognize this girl?
She been in the club?
- This is the same girl? - Yeah.
Nah, I don't know her.
She says you introduced her to some men.
I introduced her to men. I introduce a lot of people to a lot of people.
You tell me I introduced her to men. I introduced him to men.
But I don't say nothin'.
She's 14. Come on, put on your shoes, Jake.
- She's how old? - Fourteen.
She's 14? Let me see that.
Let me ask you somethin'.
You gonna tell me that that girl looks 14?
- She's 14. - I'm gonna ask you man to man.
What am I gonna say? Come on, we gotta go.
- We gotta go downtown? - That's right.
For what, because of this girl?
- You drunk? - Open the door, I'm out on bail.
I just gotta pick up one thing and I'll leave, I promise.
- Kids are sleepin'. - I won't bother them.
Let me just get somethin'.
All right, don't make no noise.
- What? - Don't make no noise.
I won't, I just gotta get this one thing.
- What are you doin'? - I gotta get $10, 000.
My lawyer says if I can spread 10, 000 around,
- I can get the case dropped. - They don't have a case against you.
Oh, no? You kiddin' me, or what?
You ever see a 14-year-old testify in court?
You saw the papers... "La Motta Out on Vice Rap."
- What are you doin' to the belt? - What difference does it make?
Can't you get the money from your friends?
Yeah, what friends?
You're gonna wake my kids up!
You're gonna wake the kids, stop it!
What's the matter with you?
Don't you put the dishes so they don't fall down?
What about the belt, Mr. La Motta?
Isn't that what you wanted to sell me, the championship belt?
- These are the jewels from the belt. - But where's the belt?
The belt of a champion is a very rare item.
I wish you'd come to me in the first place, Mr. La Motta.
You'd have had the belt and the jewels together...
Give me 2, 000 for them.
- Give me 2, 000. - 1, 500 top, that's all...
- You can't give me 2, 000? - 1, 500 top, Mr. La Motta.
- I'm sorry. I'd lose... - Give me them.
Don't tell me you're not gonna make a profit.
I know you're lyin'. Go around the corner, I bet you I get twice what you're offerin'.
I can't raise the 10, 000.
I tried, I tried. I tried a lot of places.
Yeah, but what am I gonna do?
If that's what they're gonna do, they're gonna do it, what can I do?
Then fuck 'em, let 'em do what they're gonna do.
Get in the goddamn cell, now, come on!
- That's right, can't hurt folks no more. - This is where it's at right here.
Who was the one goddamn tryin' to shirk, huh?
- You'll pull your load here, boy. - That's right.
- I don't want no more! - Get in the goddamn box!
I'll break you on one of my fuckin' farms, you son of a bitch!
- Do you hear me? - Go fuck yourself.
- Hold onto him just a minute! - I got it.
See it? See it?
Look at it, son! Live in it!
Go on, boy, live in it!
- Do you understand that? - On your mother's cunt, then!
Your mother's... !
- You cocksucker! - Live in it!
Let that son of a bitch sit, fuck him!
Fuck you!
Fuck your mother!
Dummy, dummy, dummy...
Why? Why? Why?
You motherfucker!
My hands!
Why'd you do it, why?
You're so stupid, you're so stupid,
you're so fuckin' stupid!
You're so stupid.
They called me an animal. I'm not an animal.
I'm not an animal.
Why do they treat me like this? I'm not that bad. I'm not that bad.
I'm not that guy.
Guy comes home, finds his wife in bed with another guy, the wife says,
"Look who's here... big mouth. Now the whole neighborhood will know."
Thanks. Thanks for laughin'. Spread it around a little bit.
The first night I was here, I said to the owner of the joint,
I said, "Listen, where's the toilet?"
He said, "You're in it."
Come on, let's go, let's go.
Why don't you leave me alone? I'm tryin' to do my routine.
Up yours.
Pal, you're gonna force me to make a comeback.
- Funny. - Fuck you...
And the horse you rode in on.
And the whole cavalry behind ya.
Funny man.
That's why I'm here.
Give him another drink.
Piss in it for me.
I'm now gonna introduce a woman who's made a worldwide tour
with top billing and all that other bullshit where they all hated her.
And I want you all to give her a warm welcome.
I know you're all capable of it.
You look like a bunch of junkies.
Her name is Emma 48's.
Oh, yeah! Go get it!
Taxi!
Honey...
Listen, I'm gonna take a little walk.
I got a couple of things I gotta take care of, all right?
- Will I see you later? - Yeah, here.
- Take that, I'll be home later. - Thank you.
Be careful.
Hey, what are you doin'?
Joey.
Come on, Joey. Why don't you turn around?
Come on, Joey, turn around.
Hey, Joey, come on.
Come on, Joey? What are you doin'?
Come on. What are you gettin' so angry about?
Come on, be friends.
Come on, you're my brother.
- Be friends. - I'm your brother?
Yeah, ya fuckin' bum. Give me a break, come on.
- Kiss me. - Come on, huh?
Give me a kiss, come on.
Wait, let me call my wife and kids. Don't you want them to see the kiss?
You gonna forgive and forget? It's a long time ago, forget about it.
Just give me a kiss, come on.
Come on.
You're my brother. Come on.
Come on, give me a kiss.
- What? - Come on.
- How's everything, all right? - Good.
- Everything's all right? - Yeah.
- Family? - All right.
Come on.
You don't wanna do this here, come on.
Let me call you, we'll get together in a couple days.
- You'll call me? - I will.
Don't forget.
- I'll call you. - All right.
...won it legitimately...
...and nobody could take that away from me, nobody.
Some people aren't that lucky.
Like the one that Marlon Brando played in On the Waterfront.
an up-and-comer who's now a down-and-outer.
You remember that scene in the back of the car
with his brother Charley, a small-time racket guy?
And it went somethin' like this.
"It wasn't him, Charley, it was you."
"You remember that night at the Garden, you came to my dressing room"
"and you said, 'Kid, this ain't your night. We're goin' for the price on Wilson."
"Remember that? 'This ain't your night."
"My night."
"I could've taken Wilson apart that night."
"So, what happens?"
"He gets a title shot outdoors in the ballpark, and what do I get?"
"A one-way ticket to palookaville."
"I was never no good after that night, Charley."
"It was like a peak you reach, and then it's downhill."
"It was you, Charley."
"You was my brother."
"You should've looked out for me a little bit."
"You should've looked out for me just a little bit."
"You should've taken care of me just a little bit, "
"instead of making me take them dives for the short-end money."
"You don't understand."
"I could've had class. I could've been a contender."
"I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am."
"Let's face it... it was you, Charley."
- "It was you, Charley." - How you doin', Jake?
- Everything all right? - Yeah.
- Ready? - You got about five minutes.
- You need anything? - No.
You sure?
I'm sure.
- A lot of people out there? - Yeah, it's crowded.
Go get 'em, champ.
I'm the boss, I'm the boss...